<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Slugbotics</title><link>https://slugbotics.com/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Slugbotics</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://slugbotics.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Combat Robotics</title><link>https://slugbotics.com/projects/combat_robotics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://slugbotics.com/projects/combat_robotics/</guid><description>Starting 2021, Slugbotics has a new sub-team focusing on Combat robotics competitions. Our ultimate goal is to potentially get into the televised show Battle Bots.
Slugger Slugger is our first robot created to compete in the NRL Sacramento Bot Battles regional competition. We learned valuable information about how to create and plan to build a battle bot and it helped shaped our expectations for the future.
We were successfully able to compete in the 2022 Sacramento Bot Battles and fight 2 teams there.</description></item><item><title>F1TENTH</title><link>https://slugbotics.com/projects/formula1tenth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://slugbotics.com/projects/formula1tenth/</guid><description>What is F1TENTH? F1TENTH is an autonomous robotics competition in which teams compete by developing self-driving algorithms for a one-tenth scale autonomous race car. Since teams use the same cars, the competition is centered around optimizing these algorithms to navigate around a randomized racetrack in minimum time. In partnership with UCSC’s Cyber-Physical Systems Research Center, Slugbotics members in the F1TENTH competition apply technologies such as LIDAR/SLAM, ROS, Rviz, and Gazebo to develop their car.</description></item><item><title>MATE</title><link>https://slugbotics.com/projects/mate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://slugbotics.com/projects/mate/</guid><description>What is MATE? The MATE (Marine Advanced Technical Education) Competition is an underwater robotics competition in which students create remotely operated underwater vehicles (ROVs) which are capable of performing a variety of tasks. Teams work to design, build, and test ROVs to perform various tasks, through mechanical, electrical, and programming work, and take their finished ROV to competition.
For more information, see the official MATE website.
How does the MATE Competition work?</description></item><item><title>Outreach</title><link>https://slugbotics.com/projects/outreach/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://slugbotics.com/projects/outreach/</guid><description>At Slugbotics, we aim to bring everyone into the fold of robotics. This means going above and beyond UCSC students participating in our teams, and branching out to introduce others in our community to the awesome potential of robotics.
MATE Regional Competitions Slugbotics assists MATE teams at the regional level, working with middle and high school teams to deploy and debug their ROVs, as well as scoring the competition. This assistance helps teams learn practices from college-level students on our team, as well as helps prepare them to compete in more advanced competitions, such as at the International level.</description></item><item><title>SOMARS</title><link>https://slugbotics.com/projects/somars/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://slugbotics.com/projects/somars/</guid><description>SOMARS is a sub-team of Slugbotics focused on autonomous robotics competitions. The sub-team was spawned based off the 2021 FAA Challenge competition, with its namesake deriving from the submission to the competition (System for the Oversight and Management of Autonomous Robotics Systems). It now works in collaboration with the CITRIS Institute and professor Steve McGuire, competing in CITRIS competitions against teams from UC Berkeley, UC Davis, and UC Merced.</description></item></channel></rss>