<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Slugbotics</title><link>https://slugbotics.com/</link><description>Recent content on Slugbotics</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://slugbotics.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>https://slugbotics.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://slugbotics.com/about/</guid><description>Slugbotics is a student organization at UC Santa Cruz focused on introducing students to hands-on robotics engineering, founded in 2017. In the 2018-2019 school year, our team designed, fabricated, and programmed BIG SLAB. Our second ROV, BIG SLAB is capable of performing various tasks in the MATE competition including object deployment and manipulation, water quality sensing, and autonomous analysis. Since then, we have continued to grow and learn, tackling new projects, and introducing others to the field of robotics.</description></item><item><title>Attributions</title><link>https://slugbotics.com/attributions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://slugbotics.com/attributions/</guid><description>Bulma (MIT) The MIT License (MIT) Copyright (c) 2020 Jeremy Thomas Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the &amp;#34;Software&amp;#34;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions: The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the Software.</description></item><item><title>Bios</title><link>https://slugbotics.com/team/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://slugbotics.com/team/</guid><description>Team Leads Neal Chokshi &amp;rarr;
Neal Chokshi
Pronouns: he/him
About
Neal is a second year Computer Science major, and is a Formula 1/10 Lead on Slugbotics. On the team, he leads others in developing and testing the autonomous algorithms necessary to drive the car.
&amp;nbsp;LinkedIn Andrew Gavgavian &amp;rarr;
Andrew Gavgavian
Pronouns: he/him
About
Andrew is a fourth year computer science student participating with the team for his fourth year. A previous software and networking lead for Slugbotics, Andrew now focuses on assisting others with bug fixes and development of the main control systems.</description></item><item><title>Combat Robotics</title><link>https://slugbotics.com/projects/combat_robotics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://slugbotics.com/projects/combat_robotics/</guid><description>Starting 2021, Slugbotics has a new sub-team focusing on Combat robotics competitions. Our ultimate goal is to potentially get into the televised show Battle Bots.
Slugger Slugger is our first robot created to compete in the NRL Sacramento Bot Battles regional competition. We learned valuable information about how to create and plan to build a battle bot and it helped shaped our expectations for the future.
We were successfully able to compete in the 2022 Sacramento Bot Battles and fight 2 teams there.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://slugbotics.com/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://slugbotics.com/contact/</guid><description>Email You can reach us via email at slugbotics@ucsc.edu
Social Media Please connect with us on LinkedIn, like us on Facebook, and follow us on Instagram for updates about the Slugbotics team and our underwater ROV.</description></item><item><title>F1TENTH</title><link>https://slugbotics.com/projects/formula1tenth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://slugbotics.com/projects/formula1tenth/</guid><description>What is F1TENTH? F1TENTH is an autonomous robotics competition in which teams compete by developing self-driving algorithms for a one-tenth scale autonomous race car. Since teams use the same cars, the competition is centered around optimizing these algorithms to navigate around a randomized racetrack in minimum time. In partnership with UCSC’s Cyber-Physical Systems Research Center, Slugbotics members in the F1TENTH competition apply technologies such as LIDAR/SLAM, ROS, Rviz, and Gazebo to develop their car.</description></item><item><title>Join</title><link>https://slugbotics.com/join/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://slugbotics.com/join/</guid><description>NOTE: We are no longer accepting members for the 2021-2022 season. See the bottom of this page for details.
Join Slugbotics We&amp;rsquo;re glad that you&amp;rsquo;re interested in joining our team! Here at Slugbotics, we wish to bring every aspiring engineer into the field of robotics, regardless of background. To do this, we accept new members every Fall quarter, and provide relevant trainings and onboardings to give every member the skills they need to build robots, regardless of previous experience.</description></item><item><title>MATE</title><link>https://slugbotics.com/projects/mate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://slugbotics.com/projects/mate/</guid><description>What is MATE? The MATE (Marine Advanced Technical Education) Competition is an underwater robotics competition in which students create remotely operated underwater vehicles (ROVs) which are capable of performing a variety of tasks. Teams work to design, build, and test ROVs to perform various tasks, through mechanical, electrical, and programming work, and take their finished ROV to competition.
For more information, see the official MATE website.
How does the MATE Competition work?</description></item><item><title>Onboarding</title><link>https://slugbotics.com/onboarding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://slugbotics.com/onboarding/</guid><description>Our Onboarding Process Each Fall, Slugbotics takes in new members and introduces them to skills relevant to robotics. We offer three onboarding tracks to cover the three prominent roles used in robotics engineering: Mechanical, Electronics, and Systems. These onboarding tracks are custom-designed to teach students the skills necessary to participate in our competitions and can be learned with minimal prerequisite knowledge. This makes the hands-on experience with engineering accessible to students at UCSC, regardless of prior experience or significance.</description></item><item><title>Outreach</title><link>https://slugbotics.com/projects/outreach/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://slugbotics.com/projects/outreach/</guid><description>At Slugbotics, we aim to bring everyone into the fold of robotics. This means going above and beyond UCSC students participating in our teams, and branching out to introduce others in our community to the awesome potential of robotics.
MATE Regional Competitions Slugbotics assists MATE teams at the regional level, working with middle and high school teams to deploy and debug their ROVs, as well as scoring the competition. This assistance helps teams learn practices from college-level students on our team, as well as helps prepare them to compete in more advanced competitions, such as at the International level.</description></item><item><title>SOMARS</title><link>https://slugbotics.com/projects/somars/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://slugbotics.com/projects/somars/</guid><description>SOMARS is a sub-team of Slugbotics focused on autonomous robotics competitions. The sub-team was spawned based off the 2021 FAA Challenge competition, with its namesake deriving from the submission to the competition (System for the Oversight and Management of Autonomous Robotics Systems). It now works in collaboration with the CITRIS Institute and professor Steve McGuire, competing in CITRIS competitions against teams from UC Berkeley, UC Davis, and UC Merced.</description></item><item><title>Sponsors/Donations</title><link>https://slugbotics.com/sponsors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://slugbotics.com/sponsors/</guid><description>Our Sponsors Giving Day 2021 Thank you for all of your support this Giving Day. With your help, we were able to raise over $5,000, which will help our team&amp;rsquo;s continued commitment to providing hands-on robotics experience in the UCSC community, and beyond.
Missed Giving Day? It&amp;rsquo;s not too late to contribute!
Donate Now Our Donors Shiva Abbaszadeh
Thomas Atlas
Helen A Austin
Francesc Andre Bertomeu
Neal Chokshi
Peter Craig</description></item></channel></rss>